Imagine we printed a 3D part which looks perfect
on the outside but we realize that there's a small shape error. More often
than not we think the problems come from the design. No, it is a tiny shape error
from manufacturing that we cannot see with our eye. In advanced manufacturing,
a small shape error can cause failure. They can also create safety risk and
high cost. So the question here is how can we identify this shape error before
they become expensive? My name is Evani. I'm a PhD student in industrial and
system engineering at Ohio University. To answer this question, we use 3D point
cloud. A 3D point cloud is a process of scanning an object or a part to collect
millions of points. First, we designed two test parts, a half ball and a
complex free form shape, and we printed them on a standard 3D printer. After
that, we scan each printer part with a high resolution 3D scanner. The scanner
captures hundreds of thousands of points on the surface. This gives us a digital
copy of the rear part. Then we take that point cloud that we scanned and run into
our pipeline. The pipeline automatically groups the surface into regions with
similar shape. We use unsupervised learning specifically came in classroom.
It groups the surface area that behave similarly and then we study each group.
We can see that the surface is split into colored regions for both parts.
Each region shows a different amount of geometric variation. As we can see the
clustering accuracy is about 85 to88. That means the grouping is consistent
across both shapes.
Here we compare the printed shape to the original design. From the result we can
clearly see that the curve regions change more than the flat regions. Flat
areas stay closer to the original design. curve areas drifted more. The
test shows that the curve surface can deviate up to 7 mm especially near 45°
overhang. We basically cannot see that with our eye but the pipeline can
automatically find it. Now we can measure it and show exactly where it
happens. So the impact here is we can find shape errors earlier to reduce real
work so that we can give manufacturers clear feedback about where the process
need improvement. Now we can see it, measure it and fix it. Thank you.